International Ladies Garment Workers Union. Zimmerman, Charles S. papers, 1919-1958 [bulk 1920-1945]. 5780/014
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- I. Local 22. Subject files, 1933-1958.
  - Health Insurance Plan (HIP): 1947-59. (Box 14, Folder 7a-7b)
  - Health, Mental: 1946-58. Includes Eleanor Roosevelt letter inviting CSZ to hear William Menninger (Menninger Foundation) talk on mental health, 1954. (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Hebrew Sheltering and Immigrant Aid Society (HIAS): 1935-58. (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Henson, Francis A.: 1934, 1937-38. (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Herndon Defense Committee: 1935-36. Correspondence and literature re Angelo Herndon case, sentenced to prison for violating Georgia slave insurrection law. (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Hochman, Julius: 1946. Letters on his European activities as CRT delegate. (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Hoffmitz, Laible: 1935. Includes CSZ letters on Union. (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Housing: 1950-57. Includes letters from Lincoln Square Residents Committee. (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Hunter, Elsie: 1946-55. Case; includes discrimination complaint before National Labor Relations Board. (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Hyman, Louis: 1930's. (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - I: 1936-57. Includes letters from Fenner Brockway (political secretary), Independent Labour Party re preparation for a new International, 1943-44. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - O'Dwyer letters (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Icor (Association for Jewish Colonization in the Soviet Union, Inc.): 1936-38. (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Immigration: 1936-37. (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Independent Communist Labor League and Independent Labor League of America: 1937-40. (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Independent Progressive Dressmakers, Local 22: 1940. Printed material. (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Industrial Workers of the World: 1930's. (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Institute of International Labor Research, Inc.: 1956-58. (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - International Labor Defense: 1934-38. (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union: 1934-58. Correspondence and form letters from Executive Secretary Frederick F. Umhey. (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - ILGWU, Auditing: 1937-56. (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - ILGWU, Clubs and Groups: 1937-38. (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - ILGWU, Education Department: 1933-46. Includes article, "Lest We Forget," on 22nd Anniversary of the Triangle Fire, by Fannia M. Cohn, March 1933; correspondence with Mark Starr; form letters; printed material. (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - ILGWU, Education Department.: 1947-58. (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - ILGWU, Health and Welfare Fund: 1935-58. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - ILGWU, Legal Department.: 1948-58. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Includes Federal Trade Commission vs. California Sportswear and Dress Assoc. case, 1957. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - ILGWU, Legislation: 1935-47. Includes material on the Taft-Hartley law. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - ILGWU, Jurisdictional Disputes (intra-Union): 1935-36, 1939. Includes dispute between Locals 1 and 22, 1935. (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - ILGWU, Management Engineering Department.: 1940-51. Includes reports on Leslie Fay Fashions, Inc., 1951. (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - ILGWU, Organizations, Support for: 1935-58. (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - ILGWU, Organizing Activities: 1935-38, 1954-58. (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - ILGWU, Political Department: 1937-61. Includes Gus Tyler proposal on trade union activities for Liberal Party, 1949. (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - ILGWU, Research Department.: 1937-47. (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - ILGWU, Research Department., Latin America: 1944-45. Correspondence and reports by Broadus Mitchell on feasibility of export of women's garments to Latin America. (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - ILGWU, Research Department., World War II: 1942-45. Reports, releases on laws affecting garment industry. (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - ILGWU, Training Institute: 1942, 1945-52. (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - ILGWU, Training Institute: 1953-62. (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - ILGWU, Unity House: 1933-47. (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - International Rescue Committee, Inc.: 1952-58. Includes International Relief Assoc., 1934-39; International Rescue and Relief Committee, Inc.: 1942-51. (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - International Solidarity Committee (to aid labor, socialist and democratic anti-fascists): 1946-51. (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - International Workers Order: 1934-39. (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Investigations of Shops: 1935-48. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Investments: 1929-46. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Israel: 1948-58. (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Israel Bond Drive: 1951-58. (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Italian-American Labor Council: 1942-56. (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - J: 1933-57. Includes Lyndon B. Johnson message: Dec. 1963. (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Jewish Labor Committee: 1934-July 1941. (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Jewish Labor Committee: Aug. 1941-Dec. 1941 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Jewish Labor Committee: 1945-56. (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Jewish Labor Committee: 1957-58. (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Jewish Labor Committee, Women's Division: 1949-58. (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Jewish National Workers Alliance of America: 1937-47. (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Jewish Organizations re Israel (Palestine): 1936-47. (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Joint Boards, Baltimore: 1936-48. Includes correspondence with Charles Kreindler and Angela Bambace. (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Joint Boards, Boston: 1920 's, 1937-52. Includes correspondence with Philip Kramer; printed material ('20's). (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Joint Boards, Chicago: 1920's, 1934-56. Includes correspondence with Morris Bialis. (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Joint Boards, Cleveland: 1920's, 1935-43. Includes CSZ letter to Abraham W. Katovsky, stating his position re CIO, July 1936. (Box 18, Folder 8a)
  - Joint Boards, Kansas City: 1935-36, 1954. (Box 18, Folder 8b)
  - Joint Boards, Los Angeles (Cloak): 1933-55. Includes correspondence with Paul Berg, I. Lutsky, Rose Pesotta. (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Joint Boards, New York Cloak Joint Board: 1932-54. Includes correspondence and report of Israel Feinberg; Isidore Nagler report on conditions of the Women's Coat and Suit Industry, 1954; Proposal to Establish Retirement Fund in the Coat and Suit Industry (n.d.). (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Joint Boards, N.Y. Cloak and Dress Joint Board: 1925-30. Broadsides, printed material and publi­cations, some dealing with Union internal conflict. (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Joint Boards, N.Y. Cloak and Dress Joint Board: 1925-30. Continued from above. (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Joint Boards, N.Y. Dress Joint Board: 1933-34, Includes correspondence with Phillip Kapp and Julius Hochman. (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Joint Boards, N.Y. Dress Joint Board: 1935-37. (Box 19, Folder 2a)
  - Joint Boards, N.Y. Dress Joint Board: 1938-41. Includes correspondence with Nathaniel M. Minkoff; Joint Board releases and statements. (Box 19, Folder 2b)
  - Joint Boards, N.Y. Dress Joint Board: 1942-50. (Box 19, Folder 2c)
  - Joint Boards, N.Y. Dress Joint Board: 1951-57. In c of letter from Hochman to Israel Breslow on Breslow's plan of eliminating Hochman's name as candidate to 1962 Union convention. (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Joint Boards, N.Y. Dress Joint Board: 1933-47. Agreements, correspondence, proposals, resolutions on negotiating agreement with firms and associations. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Joint Board, N.Y. Dress Joint Board: 1950-58. Agreements. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Joint Boards, N.Y., Dress Joint Board, Health and Welfare Fund: 1942-49. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Joint Boards, N.Y. Dress Joint Board, Health and Welfare Fund: 1950-58. (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Joint Boards, N.Y. Dress Joint Board, The Organizer: 1933. (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Joint Boards, N.Y. Dress Joint Board: 1920's-1960's. Printed material. (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Joint Boards, N.Y. Dress Joint Board: 1930's-60's. Printed material. (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Joint Boards, Pennsylvania (Northeast Department.): 1936-58. Includes correspondence with Min Lurye Matheson. (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Joint Boards, Philadelphia: 1925, 1935-57. (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Joint Boards, San Francisco: 1936-54. Includes correspondence with Jennie Matyas. (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Joint Boards, Seattle: 1935-36. (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Joint Boards, Winnipeg: 1935-49, 1953. Includes correspondence with Samuel Herbst on Needle Trades Workers Industrial Union of Canada. (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - K: 1937-50. (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - L: 1933-56. Includes statement for "League for One Big Union," 1933. (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - LaGuardia, Fiorello H. and Lehman, Herbert H.: 1934-42. (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Labor Bureau and Dress Industry Place­ment Unit: 1939-40. (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Labor Day: 1944-57. CSZ statements. (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Labor League for Human Rights: 1945-46. Includes Irving Brown reports on European trade union activities. (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Labor's Non-Partisan League: 1935-40. (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Lane, Jesse: 1936-37. Correspondence on CIO and Union activities. (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - League Against Fascism and Dictatorship: 1939. (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - League for Industrial Democracy, Inc.: (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - 1934-57. Includes correspondence with Harry W. Laidler. (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - League for Mutual Aid: 1936-56. (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Legislation: 1934-56. (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Legislation, Child Labor: 1934-37. (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Legislation, Civil Rights: 1938-48. (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Legislation, Foreign and Displaced Persons: 1939-48. (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Legislation, Labor: 1937-56. (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Legislation, Unemployment: 1934-57. Includes Wilbur Daniels' Statement on the Hughes-Ashberry Unemployment Insurance Bill, 1957. (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Locals 9 and 10, N.Y.C.: 1933-43. Includes correspondence with Isidore Sorkin. (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Local 22, N.Y.C.: 1925, 1930's-40's. Includes Israel Feinberg letter to Julius Portnoy on N.Y. (Cloak and Dress) Joint Board elections, 1925; printed material. (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Local 22, N.Y.C.: 1930's and 40's. Printed material, continued (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Local 22, N.Y.C.: 1930-40. Printed material, mostly announcements, leaflets from their Education, Department. (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Local 22, N.Y.C.: 1930-40's. Printed material, educational matter (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Local 22, N.Y.C.: 1930-40's. Printed educational matters. (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - V Locals 23, 25 and 31, N.Y.C.: 1930's-50's. (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Locals 35 and 48, N.Y.C.: 1937-53. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Local 60, N.Y.C.: 1934-53. Includes printed material, Dress Presser; Rank and File Group, almost all documents deal with Local elections. (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Local 60, N.Y.C.: 1934-53. (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Locals 60-A, 62 and 64, N.Y.C.: 1930's-57. (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Local 66, N.Y.C.: 1928, 1930's-56. (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Local 89, N.Y.C.: 1926, 1930's-40. Correspondence with Luigi Antonini and printed material. (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Local 91, N.Y.C.: 1933-43. (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Locals 98 and 99, N.Y.C.: 1942-54. (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Locals 102 and 105, N.Y.C.: Local 106, Baltimore, Md.: 1937-58. Includes GEB Special Committee minutes and reports re separate charter for Snow Suit and Legging Workers, Local 105, 1939. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Local 117, N.Y.C.: 1936-54. Includes printed material of Locals 1 and 17 prior to merger as Local 117 in February 1936. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Local 117, N.Y.C.: 1936-54. (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Local 120, Decatur, Ill; Local 122, Atlanta, Ga.: 1935-38. Includes correspondence with John S. Martin. (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Local 132, N.Y.C.: 1932-43. Includes by-laws; Martin Feldman case, 1938. (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Locals 142, 145 and 148, N.J.: 1935-37. (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Local 155, N.Y.C.: 1933-Aug. 1936. Correspondence with Louis Nelson, releases, statements. (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Local 155, N.Y.C.: Sept. 1936-56. (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Local 155, N.Y.C.: 1933-53. Printed material, almost all dealing with Local elections. (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Locals, Southern: 1949-57. Includes John S. Martin and Abraham Plotkin letters (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Locals, Miscellaneous: 1920's-30. Includes Local 2, N.Y.C., and Local 184, Seattle, Wash. (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Local Managers' (N.Y. Dress) Conferences: 1933, 1939-45. Minutes. (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Local Mgrs.' (N.Y. Dress) Conferences: 1952-55. (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - log. Mgrs.' (N.Y. Dress) Conferences: 1956-58. (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Lurye (Matheson), Min: 1936-44. (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Lurye, William, Case: 1949-50. Includes Min Lurye (Matheson) letters (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Lurye, William, Case: 1951-52. Includes copies of correspondence between Julius Hochman and District Attorney's office. (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Lurye, William, Case: 1949. Newspaper clippings. (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Lurye, William, Case: 1950. Newspaper clippings. (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - M: 1934-55. (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Madwin, Max, Case: 1942. (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Manuscripts and Outlines by CSZ on Union and Political Subjects: 1920's-40's. Contains some completed articles and statements. (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Manuscripts and Outlines: 1920's-40's. (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - May Day Celebrations: 1930's-40's. Includes correspondence, printed material on Local participation. (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - May Day Celebrations: 1930's-40's. (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Medical Matters: 1939-58. (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Membership Meetings, Local 22: 1933-41. Outlines and minutes. (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Membership Meetings, Local 22: 1942-50. (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Membership Meetings, Local 22: 1951-57. (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Minkoff, Nathaniel M.: 1931-33. Includes activities of Educational Com­mittee of the Socialist Party, Bronx Branch; personal material. (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Minkoff, Nathaniel M.: 1934-49. (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Minority Crafts Branch; Local 22: 1932-34. Minutes. (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Minutes of Various Committees: 1931-47. (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous Documents: 1932-39. Mostly letters from Local members. (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Documents: 1940-57. (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Documents: 1930's-40's. Mostly printed material; includes non­union matters. (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Documents. Printed material. (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Mooney, Tom: 1929-40. Includes letters from Tom Mooney Molders' Defense Committee. (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - N: 1933-50. (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - National Association for the Advance­ment of Colored People (NAACP): 1933-58. Includes correspondence with Herbert Hill, Jackie Robinson, Walter White, Roy Wilkins on civil rights and labor matters. (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - NAACP: 1962. Representatives Adam Clayton Powell and Herbert Zelenko investigation of Union discrimination; includes AFL-CIO statement, Herbert Hill testimony, copy of A. Philip Randolph Itr. to David Dubinsky, CSZ resignation statement as trustee from Legal Defense and Educational Fund of NAACP; Jewish Labor Committee reports. (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - NAACP: 1962. ILGWU-NAACP controversy, continued (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - National Committee to Abolish the Poll Tax: 1941-48. (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - National Committee for Labor Israel, Histadrut (prior to 1940 National Com­mittee for Labor Palestine): 1934-48. (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - National Committee for Labor Israel, Histadrut: 1949-58. (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - National Community Relations Advisory Council: 1944-58. (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - National Negro Congress: 1936-37. (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - National Recovery Administration: 1933-34. Includes reports of Commission. (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - National Sharecroppers Fund, Inc.: 1935, 1940-48. (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - National Urban League: 1933-49. Includes correspondence with James H. Hubert (N.Y. Urban League) on campaign to organize Negro dressmakers, 1933. (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - National Urban League: 1951-55. (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - National Urban League: 1956-59. Includes correspondence with Lester B. Granger, Thomas Young; CSZ address at Urban League Conference, 1959. (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - National Urban League: 1937. Memorandum, arbitration proceedings between Union and Urban League following Union's picketing Chicago Urban League office; correspondents includes Morris Bialis, Abraham Plotkin, David Dubinsky, Arnold Hill (director), Department. of Industrial Relations of League. (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Needle Trades Workers Industrial Union: 1933-35. Includes NTWIU proposal to improve conditions of workers in dress industry and for united front to conduct strike, June 1933, and Executive Board reply, July; Irving Potash proposal to unify for strike and to establish one Dressmakers Union, Aug. 1933; Ben Gold letter to unify dressmakers into one union and CSZ statement, Aug. 1934. (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Negro Garment Workers: 1930's-40's. (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Negro Labor Committee: 1935-53. Includes correspondence Frank R. Crosswaith. (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - New Leader: 1943-46. (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - New York Dressmakers' Strike: 1933, 1936, 1947. (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - New York State Federation of Labor: 1935-57. Includes Union resolutions submitted at State conventions. (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Newspapers, Correspondence: 1934-58. Includes CSZ letter to Russian newspaper, Izvestia, replying to letter addressed to Local 22 from Russian worker, 1955. (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - 0: 1945, 1957. Letters from Paul Olberg, 1945; correspondence with Rita Oberbeck, 1957. (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Organization Committee, Local 22: 1933-48. Minutes, reports. (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Organization for Rehabilitation Through Training - In Industry and Agriculture (ORT): 1935-48. Includes ORT activities in Europe. (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Organizations, Support for: 1937-58. Includes National Foundation for Infantile Paralysis, 1957; War Relief Fund, American Society for Russian Relief, Inc., 1945-46. (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Organizing Activities, Local 22: 1949-57. (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - P: 1937-57. (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Permits to Work: 1933-34. (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Pesotta, Rose: 1934-44. (Box 29, Folder la)
  - Pioneer Youth of America, Inc.: 1933-48. (Box 29, Folder 1b)
  - Poetry and Songs, Local 22 and Affiliated Locals: 1930's-50's. (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Politics: 1936-55. Includes Thomas E. Dewey letters during campaign for district attorney, 1937; CSZ letter to Dean Acheson on combatting Communist aggression, 1950; Fellowship of Reconciliation, 1955. (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Politics, Liberal Party: 1952-58. Includes correspondence with Ben Davidson, CSZ speech at Liberal Party-Trade Union Council, 1958. (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Politics, Liberal Party, Dressmakers Liberal Party Club: 1949, 1954-57. (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Politics, Social Democratic Federation of N.Y.C.: 1937-57. (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Politics, Socialist Party: 1935-58. Includes correspondence with Norman Thomas, Socialist organi­zations, re civil liberties, political matters, war policy, communism. (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Politics, Trade Union Committee for a Labor Party: 1936. Letters from Elmer Brown. (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Progressive Groups, Dressmakers Pro­gressive Group, Local 22: 1933-50 's. Letters, releases, statements, reports, printed material mainly dealing with Local elections. (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Progressive Groups, Dressmakers Pro­gressive Group, Local 22: 1933-50's. Continued (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Progressive Groups, Dressmakers Pro­gressive Group, Local 22: 1933-50's. Continued (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Progressive Groups, Dressmakers Pro­gressive Group, Local 22: 1933-50's. Continued (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Progressive Groups, Dressmakers Pro­gressive Group, Local 22: 1933-50's. Continued (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Progressive Groups, Locals: 1935-36. Includes minutes of Needle Trades Pro­gressive Groups. (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Progressive Groups, Locals: 1935-36. Continued (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Progressive Unionist: 1936. Council of Needle Trades Progressive Groups. (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Progressive Trade Unionists: 1935-36. Correspondence with Mildred Allmendinger. (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Provisional Labor Committees: 1936-39. (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Puerto Rico: 1935-60. Includes correspondence with William D. Lopez; Robert Gladnick, Nelson A. Rockefeller letter re advertise­ment, "We, Too, Fight Delinquency," 1959. (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Puerto Rico, Labor Advisory Committee on Puerto Rican Affairs: 1952-54. (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Puerto Rico, Labor Advisory Committee on Puerto Rican Affairs: 1955-57. (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Puerto Rico, Mayor's Committee on Puerto Rican Affairs in NYC: 1954-57. (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Puerto Rico, Needle Workers Union of Puerto Rico, Local 300, ILGWU: 1934-37, 1939. Includes correspondence with Teresa Anglero, Rose Pesotta, re organizing activities, Local matters, Code for Needlework Industry (n.d.). (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Puerto Rico, Wage and Hour Hearings: 1955-57. (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Puerto Rico, Wage and Hour Hearings: 1955-57. (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - R: 1936-58. Includes correspondence re Remington-Rand Co. strike, 1936-37; letters to Franklin D. Roosevelt re labor and war matters, 1942-43. (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Racketeering, Anti-: 1949-54. Correspondence, reports, newspaper clippings re garment industry and other unions. (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Rand School of Social Science: 1936-55. (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Rank and File, Left Wing, and Opposition Groups, Local 22: 1932-43. Correspondence, resolutions, statements, minutes and form letters (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Rank and File, Left Wing and Opposition Groups, Local 22: 1944-55. Correspondence, continued (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Rank and File, Left Wing and Opposition Groups, Local 22: l930's-50's. Printed material dealing with Local elections, and all facets of Local activities. (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Rank and File, Left Wing and Opposition Groups, Local 22: n.d. Printed material. (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Rank and File, Left Wing and Opposition Groups, Local 22: 1930's. Printed material, Dressmakers Unity Committee of International Members and the Industrial Union. (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Rank and File, Left Wing and Opposition Groups, Local 22: 1930's. Printed material, United Dressmakers Committee of the Left Wing Group and Active Members Group. (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Rank and File, Left Wing and Opposition Groups, Local 22: 1930's. Includes Dressmakers United Front Committee, Dressmakers Industrial Union. (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Rank and File, Left Wing and Opposition Groups, Local 22: 1930's. Publications, includes Dressmakers Voice. (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Rank and File, Left Wing and Opposition Groups to ILGWU: 1920's-30's. Includes Left Wing and Rank and File Groups, Locals 10, 22, 60, 89. (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Red Cross Drives: 1948-57. (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Releases and Announcements: 1933-34. (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Releases and Announcements: 1935-36. (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Releases and Announcements: 1937-39. (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Releases and Announcements: 1940-42. (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Releases and Announcements: 1943-46. (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Releases and Announcements: 1947-50's. (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Religious Matters: 1936-46. (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Religious Matters, National Religion and Labor Foundation: 1937-48. (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Resolutions, by Executive Board or Membership Meetings of Local 22: 1933-42. Includes Executive Board resolution protesting GEB action in removing Local 9 administration from office, Jan. 1934. (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Resolutions by Executive Board or Membership Meetings of Local 22: 1946-57. (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Resolutions Submitted by Workers of Shops: 1930's-40's. (Box 32, Folder 9)